<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Ben McLaren - bybenmclaren</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Ben McLaren - bybenmclaren</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 15:31:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Horizontal scrollbars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/horizontal-scrollbars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 15:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/horizontal-scrollbars/</guid>
      <description>We are going to make a scrollbar that will scroll horizontally as the user scrolls vertically down the page. This is a nice feature to have especially on longer pages as you can quickly display to the user how far through an article they are.&#xA;We need to use JQuery for this so make sure that you have imported the JQuery library. See this site as a demonstration of what we are going to build.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEO in Rails</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/seo-in-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 17:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/seo-in-rails/</guid>
      <description>SEO is an important but often overlooked aspect of web development. It is essential in ensuring the maximum exposure for your website and good SEO can really improve traffic to your sites.&#xA;Dynamic page titles Imagine that we have a review website. We might want to have the title of our webpage change depending on which page of our website the user is on.&#xA;Rails has a helper method called content_for that allows us to do just that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Image Overlays</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/image-overlays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 10:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/image-overlays/</guid>
      <description>An overlay seems like it would be something difficult to achieve however, it is actually relatively simple and it can be done with just CSS.&#xA;For this example, let&amp;rsquo;s assume that you wish to overlay text on an image when you hover over it. To do this let&amp;rsquo;s first take a look at some HTML.&#xA;&amp;lt;section&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;photo&amp;#34; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;overlay&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt; some text &amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;#34;my-image.jpg&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/section&amp;gt; Above is some simple HTML code for an image contained in a section.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexbox grid layouts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/flexbox-grid-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 10:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/flexbox-grid-layouts/</guid>
      <description>Flexbox is a very powerful tool and it is one that can be used to create many different layouts.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s say that you wish to lay out a selection of images on a page in a grid style. In the past this would have been difficult to achieve inlvolving developers needing to &amp;lsquo;hack&amp;rsquo; their way around it using floats. However, with only a few lines of code flexbox is able to create a grid.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Inline navigation bar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/an-inline-navigation-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 13:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/an-inline-navigation-bar/</guid>
      <description>One of the key components on my site is the navigation bar. Initially, I had attempted to create this using floats however, I quickly realised that this was not an effective way of constructing this element. It was at this point that I researched Flexbox and how it can be used to make a responsive component.&#xA;Setting out the HTML &amp;lt;header class=&amp;#34;header&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ul class=&amp;#34;nav&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li class=&amp;#34;nav-link&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;work.html&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Work&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li class=&amp;#34;nav-link&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;articles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making responsive text</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/making-responsive-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 11:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/making-responsive-text/</guid>
      <description>Websites need to look good across a multitude of screens and therfore it is essential that a site is responsive so that a user&amp;rsquo;s experience is not affected by their choice of screen size. I encountered a problem whilst building this site that was causing some of my headers to be cut off of the page when the browser size was reduced. I had previously tried using margins and padding to try and fix this issue however, some research led me to media queries.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
